<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HackTheBox on ajdintrejic</title>
    <link>https://ajdin.io/categories/hackthebox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HackTheBox on ajdintrejic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 09:03:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ajdin.io/categories/hackthebox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HackTheBox :: Openadmin Write Up</title>
      <link>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/openadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 09:03:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/openadmin/</guid>
      <description>Reconnaissance Let&amp;rsquo;s see what have we got here with nmap.
nmap -sC -sV -O -oA nmap/initial 10.10.10.171 -sC: run default script scan -sV: probe open ports to determine service/version info -O: OS detection -oA: output OS detection, version detection, script scanning, and traceroute Nmap returns the results quick as it by default scans only for most popular 1000 ports, so lets scan all the ports while we investigate the initial nmap scan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackTheBox :: Mango Write Up</title>
      <link>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/mango/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 13:28:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/mango/</guid>
      <description>Reconnaissance Let’s run nmap,
sudo nmap -sV -sC -O -oA nmap/initial 10.10.10.162 We have to use https for this website on port 80, and we can get this “search page”. We can see some kind of analytics page in the top right corner.
Getting user account I checked the /robots.txt, also ran gobuster, nothing useful there. The SSL certificate wasn’t valid so I took a look a there and we have a page reference: staging-order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackTheBox :: Postman Write Up</title>
      <link>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/postman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 13:28:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajdin.io/posts/htb/postman/</guid>
      <description>Reconnaissance Let’s run a quick nmap scan as always.
# nmap -sV -sC -O -oA nmap/initial 10.10.10.160 Short explanation:
-sV Version detection -sC Script scan -O Enable OS detection -oA Output to all formats For a more detailed explanation click here.
While I wait for this to be finished I’ll start a full nmap scan.
# nmap -sV -sC -O -p- -oA nmap/initial 10.10.10.160 As usual we have port 22 and port 80 running, but here we also have http protocol running on port 10000, let’s enumerate on those pages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>